<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>mattcolewilson.com</title>
<description>Still postin'.</description>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<atom:link href="https://mattcolewilson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
<title>Now.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/now.jpg"/></p><p>Bummed that Cohost is <a href="https://cohost.org/staff/post/7611443-cohost-to-shut-down" target="_blank">going away</a>. But newly energized and determined to have a nice time online. Life IRL is going well. We’ve been doing one of those big gradient puzzles. It's nice.</p>
<p>Playing: Elden Ring (Just got the DLC!)<br/>
Listening: Busdriver - Perfect Hair<br/>
Reading: Cold Hand in Mine - R. Aickman</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#00</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Quick Plug for FAMICLUB</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/famiclub.png"/></p><p>In case you somehow missed it, I want to invite you to join Famiclub. It’s a cozy little forum for discussing video games, graphic design, and related subjects. My buddy William Hackworth set it up in Spring of 2023 and it’s been one of my favorite places to hang out online since. There’s some real good people there, some good conversation, and even the occasional design jam. It’s a very welcoming community and if you are reading this, you are almost certainly the target audience.</p> <p>It has grown a little quiet over the last few months, but I am personally planning on being more active there and I hope <b>you</b> will, too! Here’s a link: <a href="https://forum.fami.club/">https://forum.fami.club/</a>.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:11:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://forum.fami.club</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#09</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rostin’ Ain't Easy</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I do think there's value in having some sort of barrier between your thoughts and the rest of the world. But I also wish some of this indie web stuff was a bit easier. I personally enjoy setting up all these things (maybe even more than actually posting). But I also know most of my IRL friends would absolutely not go through the hurdles of doing all this stuff. And, you know, I totally get it.</p> <p>I wish that some saintly developer would come along and create an open source app that would do all the heavy lifting. I feel like the infrastructure is in place and someone with the know-how could create an extremely limited and non-interactive “social media” <i>“platform”</i> that relies on RSS. (I don't know about you but that sounds Good and worth the time and effort, lol.)</p> <p>Like, it'd be <b>lovely</b> to just have a little box that I could type a post into and then have that add an entry to my feed that my readers would get next time they check in. I know you can rig up a generator to help with this, but that still requires the manual update/upload/etc.</p> <p>I dunno, I am sure I am asking for too much. But it seems like there’s some missing modern convenience. I do need to read more about the history of RSS and its uses. I understand that people have created RSS-only blogs before. Maybe they’ve figured out an easier process than what I’m doing.</p> <p>But yeah, I am having a nice time overall. I'm just saying that this current state would be a very hard sell to my non-indie web enthusiast friends. And oh well. So it goes. I'll be over here feeling that much cooler updating my secret blog made up of hand-written code that only special applications can properly decipher (lol).</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 06:09:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#08</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Secret Sneak Peek for Subscribers Only</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I'm going to release a dungeon synth EP in November! I barely know what I'm doing when it comes to making music, so don't get excited. But I've had a good time putting together four (and a half) tracks for this thing. It's all heavily inspired by dungeon crawler videogames. (Was aiming for a Shadow Tower vibe, but kinda landed somewhere else.) You can listen to and/or download an MP3 called Summoner's Ghost <a href="https://mattcolewilson.com/audio/summoners-ghost.mp3" target="_blank">using this link</a>, if you want! And maybe this embed will work: <audio controls src="https://mattcolewilson.com/audio/summoners-ghost.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"></audio></p> <p>The overall project is titled <b>Ashen Altar</b> and this EP is going to be called </i>Remnants</i>. It also has a really cool cover that I'm excited to share. More to come!</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#07</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Notes on RSS and Rosting</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Finally figured out the basics of setting up an RSS feed. Sharing my notes, in case it can be of help to anyone else. This also goes over the basics of rosting (RSS direct posting). <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1NviGoDnR0LSOE6cJoBmITm_YIOM7EA5yMeydDpYkcXU/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Check it out</a>.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#05</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cat Pic</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-arcade.jpg"/></p><p>I will 100% post exclusive cat pics here. This is an old one that I had on hand to test things out. So, uh, stay tuned.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#04</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Maybe TMI but I got a vasectomy earlier this month and I highly recommend it. Not a big deal and it guarantees a bright, childless future. Posting this because if I had known how easy it was earlier, I probably would have done it years ago.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#03</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Getting Into Cassette Tapes</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-cassette-player.jpg"/></p><p>I'm into cassette tapes again. The last time I regularly used a cassette player was probably in middle school. Having a very nice time with this lil guy from Turntable Labs. Blessed to not be an audiophile.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#02</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hello world. (First post.)</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>When all the good places to post go away, you have to create your own. This is a total ripoff (with permission) of <a href="https://www.whack.zone" target="_blank">whack.zone</a>. I plan on posting little updates and occasional thoughts here. Thanksss for following the feed!</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#01</guid>
</item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
