<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>mattcolewilson</title>
<description>Still postin'.</description>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<atom:link href="https://mattcolewilson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
<title>New Page</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-arcade-2.jpg" alt="A mostly white cat stands in front of a white wall."/></p><p>Made a <a href="https://mattcolewilson.com/photos.html">new page</a> on my website. It's a photo stream extension of the Now page (but with a few more photos). I like it, but it is making my posting process even more difficult, lol. (Now anytime I post an update with an image, I'm gonna add it to the Now page, the photos page, and this RSS feed.) But websites are fun, for real, for real.</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 15:45:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/photos</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#32</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<title>More Cassette Tapes</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-tapes.jpg" alt="Two small stacks of cassette tapes sitting on a white desk. The 12 tapes are: Bad Brains (self-titled), Björk (Post and Vespertine), Gel (Only Constant), Chat Pile (Cool World), Jeff Rosenstock (Post), Godflesh (Post Self), Iron Butterfly (In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida), Bob Dylan (Highway 61 Revisited and The Basementa Tapes), and Mountain (On Top)."/></p><p>Check out my little cassette tape collection! Recent acquisitions – from Love Garden Sounds in Lawrence – include Vespertine by Björk, the Bad Brains self-titled debut, and Jeff Rosenstock's Post. (I kinda regret getting Post instead of Hellmode. So it goes.)</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:50:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#31</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>I am now on Bear Blog</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Seems like a nice place. Here's my link: <a href="https://malyzar.bearblog.dev">https://malyzar.bearblog.dev</a></p><p>Hope you're having a nice day. If you're interested in a lil treat, maybe try out the Witch's Brew from Sonic. It's very good, imo!</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 11:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#30</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Kinda want to make a plain text website and/or start using bearblog to write more. But I will probably end up just playing Elden Ring instead of doing either of these things.</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#29</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Andrew Elmore dropped a <a href="https://satellitesound.bandcamp.com/album/wavebeam" target="_blank">new album</a> earlier this month. Almost snuck by me, just finding out now. It's great. PSP beats! Do it!</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 22:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#28</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I'm (what feels like) half way through the Shadow of the Erdtree DLC and it fuckin' rocks. Also listening to <a href="https://www.bonfireside.chat/" target="_blank">Bonfireside Chat</a> as I go and it's such a wonderful way to experience a game. Highly recommended.</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#27</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-rex.jpg" alt="A black cat lying on a desk."/></p><p>Had a nice three-day weekend and am feeling refreshed. Went to a pumpkin patch with some friends and then took a day trip to Lawrence, KS. Poked around downtown, visited the art museum, etc. Had a good time, but nothing feels better than coming home.</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 09:45:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#26</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I'm now on Record Club. (It's like GoodReads or Letterboxd, but for music.) Seems neat! <a href="https://record.club/malyzar">Check it out.</a></p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#25</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Now (2024.10.07)</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-coolworld.jpg" alt="A hand holding a cassette tape titled Cool World by the noise rock band Chat Pile. The cover includes an image of a large cross standing in a gloomy midwestern landscape."/></p>
<p>Got the <a href="https://youtu.be/YnDWVWZrZrE?si=t_-KwpI4korc5L4D">new Chat Pile</a> cassette and am listening to it for the first time while posting this update. So far, so good. Last night I watched the movie Another Round (2020) and really enjoyed it. Not much else is new. Another week, just getting started.</p>
<p>Playing: Elden Ring (knee-deep in the DLC)<br/>
Listening: Chat Pile – Cool World<br/>
Reading: Halloween – Curtis Richards</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 12:25:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#24</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>The latest Now post from Jack Grimes is a must read. Posted September 30th, goes for the jugular. Bleak Americana. Highly recommended: <a href="https://www.jackis.online/now">https://www.jackis.online/now</a></p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 21:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#23</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-arcade.jpg" alt="A (mostly) white cat lying on a white bed with sun coming through a window in the background."/></p>Anyway, look at my cute cat.</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#22</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<title>RIP Cohost.org.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.10-eggbug.jpg" alt="An embroidered patch featuring an illustration of Eggbug, the Cohost.org mascot, surrounded by text that reads FRIEND OF EGGBUG - COHOST.ORG. The patch rests on a window sill, a backyard can be seen through the window in the distance."/></p>I had a nice time. I'm also trying to avoid over inflating that website's importance. But it shutting down feels like the end of something. A last gasp. Social media is essentially over, as far as I'm concerned. Personal sites, forums, and RSS feeds are the future. And that's not a bad way to go, I guess.</p><p>Speaking of, I don't have any sort of comment section, but feel free to email me at mattcolewilson at gmail dot com. We can still have a social internet!</p>]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:15:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#21</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Puzzle update: we (finally) finished and all the pieces were present! I take back the disparaging comments I made earlier about our cats. They're good boys, afterall.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#20</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Five Favorite Feeds to Follow (FFF2F)</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Below are five of my current favorite RSS feeds (in alphabetical order). You should check these out, if you haven’t already. What feeds are <b>you</b> following? Do a post about it or maybe even send me your list via email to <a href="mailto:mattcolewilson@gmail.com">mattcolewilson@gmail.com</a>. Thanks!</p>
<p><b><a href="https://adamledoux.net/blog/feed.xml">adam le doux</a></b></br>The personal blog of adam le doux, an indie game dev and the creator of <a href="https://bitsy.org">Bitsy</a>. Posts video game stuff, cat pics, and occasionally dabbles in rosting. You know, the good stuff.</p>
<p><b><a href="http://www.ribbonblack.com/feeds/posts/default?alt=rss">Ribbon Black</a></b></br>A blog showcasing video game ephemera, including a lot of old Famicase stuff. Beautiful photos and great write-ups. I have accidentally found myself in these archives many times over the years. Glad to now be a subscriber.</p>
<p><b><a href="https://rubymayvalentine.net/rss.xml">Ruby May Valentine</a></b><br>Personal posts from Ruby May Valentine, the inventor of rosting as we know it. Posts a wide variety of content, including video game stuff, artwork, and occasional pet pics. (Also, Ruby is largely responsible for me figuring out how to set up my own RSS feed.)</p>
<p><b><a href="https://sweetfish.site/feed.xml">sweetfish.site</a></b><br>Indie game dev and Cohost stalwart. Has a beautiful website that you should check out. Recently moved RSS feeds, but I am confident that more posts are on the way.</p>
<p><b><a href="https://whack.zone/feed">whack dot zone</a></b><br>Posts from graphic designer Will Hackworth. Good dude and top dog at Famiclub! His site is also the direct inspiration for my current posting setup. Go compare them!</p>
<p><hr></p>
<p>PS: Approximately three out of five of these are people I found via Cohost. RIP Cohost!</p>
<p>PPS: Look forward to <b>Five <i>More</i> Favorite Feeds to Follow</b> (FMFF2F). Coming soon.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 21:15:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#19</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Now (2024.09.29)</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-eldenring2.jpg"/></p><p>Having a very nice weekend at home. Finishing a puzzle, getting way into a novel, reading RSS feeds, hitting up the breakfast diner. You know, cool shit like that.</p>
<p>Playing: Elden Ring (knee-deep in the DLC)<br/>
Listening: Death Grips – The Powers That B<br/>
Reading: Perfume – Patrick Süskind</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 10:25:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#18</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Listened to sad music all morning and have bummed myself out. (This is a rake I will continue to step on.) Anyway, I've said this before, but <a href="https://youtu.be/oHgCXhY6kZ0?si=VY9WeyeylX3uVFXc" target="_blank">If I Didn't Have Your Love</a> by Leonard Cohen is one of the best love songs ever written.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 15:25:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#17</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Pushed a small update to the Links page. There's now (the start of) an 88x31 button wall. <a href="https://mattcolewilson.com/links.html#buttons">Check it out</a> and visit some cool websites.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 16:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#16</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Where the magic happens.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-office.jpg"/><p>I strongly recommend grabbing a photo of the places you spend your time. It's nice to have something to look back on if things change.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#15</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I am now prepared for the Cohost shutdown. Got a solid setup going here. Finished making a list of the people I want to keep an eye on. And I’m becoming a total RSS sicko. See you on the other side.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 16:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#14</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Seeing those giant skeletons around town. The greatest innovation in Halloween decor that's happened in my lifetime, by far.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 16:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#13</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-night-drive.jpg" alt="A moody, low-quality photo of a sunset taken from inside of a car. The windshield wipers and the car's dashboard are silhouetted in the foreground. The sky is dark and a line of trees block the left half of the horizon. The whole image is slightly blurred by the motion of the car, which appears to be turning onto a road."/></p> <p>Took this photo a couple nights ago. Feels like something I would've taken with my shitty phone in like 2008 (non-derogatory).</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 16:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#12</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Puzzle Progress Report</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>The cats finally fucked with the puzzle. Found some pieces down the hall and one in the linen closet. It was bound to happen, I guess. This whole thing will probably end in frustration. So it goes.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#11</guid>
</item>
  
<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>We’ve been going to the gym lately, which has been great overall. (Who would have thought?) But the big thing they don’t tell you is how much time it takes. Work a full-time job and then <i>also</i> go to another place and exercise for like an hour? A total day melter.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://forum.fami.club</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#10</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Quick Plug for FAMICLUB</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/famiclub.png"/></p><p>In case you somehow missed it, I want to invite you to join Famiclub. It’s a cozy little forum for discussing video games, graphic design, and related subjects. My buddy William Hackworth set it up in Spring of 2023 and it’s been one of my favorite places to hang out online since. There’s some real good people there, some good conversation, and even the occasional design jam. It’s a very welcoming community and if you are reading this, you are almost certainly the target audience.</p> <p>It has grown a little quiet over the last few months, but I am personally planning on being more active there and I hope <b>you</b> will, too! Here’s a link: <a href="https://forum.fami.club/">https://forum.fami.club/</a>.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:11:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://forum.fami.club</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#09</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rostin’ Ain't Easy</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I do think there's value in having some sort of barrier between your thoughts and the rest of the world. But I also wish some of this indie web stuff was a bit easier. I personally enjoy setting up all these things (maybe even more than actually posting). But I also know most of my IRL friends would absolutely not go through the hurdles of doing all this stuff. And, you know, I totally get it.</p> <p>I wish that some saintly developer would come along and create an open source app that would do all the heavy lifting. I feel like the infrastructure is in place and someone with the know-how could create an extremely limited and non-interactive “social media” <i>“platform”</i> that relies on RSS. (I don't know about you but that sounds Good and worth the time and effort, lol.)</p> <p>Like, it'd be <b>lovely</b> to just have a little box that I could type a post into and then have that add an entry to my feed that my readers would get next time they check in. I know you can rig up a generator to help with this, but that still requires the manual update/upload/etc.</p> <p>I dunno, I am sure I am asking for too much. But it seems like there’s some missing modern convenience. I do need to read more about the history of RSS and its uses. I understand that people have created RSS-only blogs before. Maybe they’ve figured out an easier process than what I’m doing.</p> <p>But yeah, I am having a nice time overall. I'm just saying that this current state would be a very hard sell to my non-indie web enthusiast friends. And oh well. So it goes. I'll be over here feeling that much cooler updating my secret blog made up of hand-written code that only special applications can properly decipher (lol).</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 06:09:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#08</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Secret Sneak Peek for Subscribers Only</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>I'm going to release a dungeon synth EP in November! I barely know what I'm doing when it comes to making music, so don't get excited. But I've had a good time putting together four (and a half) tracks for this thing. It's all heavily inspired by dungeon crawler videogames. (Was aiming for a Shadow Tower vibe, but kinda landed somewhere else.) You can listen to and/or download an MP3 called Summoner's Ghost <a href="https://mattcolewilson.com/audio/summoners-ghost.mp3" target="_blank">using this link</a>, if you want! And maybe this embed will work: <audio controls src="https://mattcolewilson.com/audio/summoners-ghost.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"></audio></p> <p>The overall project is titled <b>Ashen Altar</b> and this EP is going to be called <i>Remnants</i>. It also has a really cool cover that I'm excited to share. More to come!</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#07</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Notes on RSS and Rosting</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Finally figured out the basics of setting up an RSS feed. Sharing my notes, in case it can be of help to anyone else. This also goes over the basics of rosting (RSS direct posting). <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1NviGoDnR0LSOE6cJoBmITm_YIOM7EA5yMeydDpYkcXU/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Check it out</a>.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#05</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cat Pic</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-arcade.jpg" alt="A photo of a pudgy white cat lying on a yellow chair. The cat is slightly leaning up and appears to be looking slightly below the camera, with a tired and slightly annoyed expression on his face."/></p><p>I will 100% post exclusive cat pics here. This is an old one that I had on hand to test things out. So, uh, stay tuned.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#04</guid>
</item>

<item>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Maybe TMI but I got a vasectomy earlier this month and I highly recommend it. Not a big deal and it guarantees a bright, childless future. Posting this because if I had known how easy it was earlier, I probably would have done it years ago.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#03</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Getting Into Cassette Tapes</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-cassette-player.jpg" alt="A cassette player and headphones next to two cassette tapes. One of the tapes is labelled GODFLESH and the other is Björk's iconic 1995 album Post."/></p><p>I'm into cassette tapes again. The last time I regularly used a cassette player was probably in middle school. Having a very nice time with this lil guy from Turntable Labs. Blessed to not be an audiophile.</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#02</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hello world.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>When all the good places to post go away, you have to create your own. This is a total ripoff (with permission) of <a href="https://www.whack.zone" target="_blank">whack.zone</a>. I plan on posting little updates and occasional thoughts here. Thanksss for following the feed!</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#01</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Now (2024.09.16)</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://mattcolewilson.com/images/2024.09-eldenring.jpg"/></p><p>Bummed that Cohost is <a href="https://cohost.org/staff/post/7611443-cohost-to-shut-down" target="_blank">going away</a>. But newly energized and determined to have a nice time online. Life IRL is going well. We’ve been doing one of those big gradient puzzles. It's nice.</p>
<p>Playing: Elden Ring (Just got the DLC!)<br/>
Listening: Busdriver - Perfect Hair<br/>
Reading: Cold Hand in Mine - R. Aickman</p> ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 04:20:00 CDT</pubDate>
<link>https://mattcolewilson.com/now</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">rost#00</guid>
</item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
